Guide to the Deane Keller Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- World War II, 1940-1960 (inclusive), 1943-1946 (bulk); Series III
  - Photographs
    - Envelopes [positives, n.d.]
      - "Naples, Vomero, jail, nuns, hospital" (Box 30, Folder 154)
      - "Office portraits" (Box 30, Folder 155)
      - "Paesteum, Battipaglia, Salerno" (Box 30, Folder 156)
      - "Paesteum, Sorento" [includes images of art deposits in Alto Adige] (Box 30, Folder 157)
      - "Pisa" (Box 31, Folder 158 - 160)
      - "Pisa?" [includes images of art deposits at Campo Tures, bomb damage to Lucca Cathedral] (Box 31, Folder 161)
      - "Pisa, Charley" [includes images of protection efforts on Massaccio's Brancacci Chapel, Florence] (Box 31, Folder 162)
      - "Pisa, Florence, 4 R Major Sidney Waugh" (Box 31, Folder 163)
      - "Pisa, Col. Mitchell" [bomb damage to the Campo Santo, frescoes and exposed underdrawing] (Box 31, Folder 164)
      - "Pisa, San Miniato" (Box 31, Folder 165)
      - "Po Area?" (Box 31, Folder 166)
      - "Po River, pontoon bridge" (Box 31, Folder 167)
      - "Red Cross, II Corps, Mongtidoro, Col. Wray" (Box 31, Folder 168)
      - "Rome" (Box 31, Folder 169 - 170)
      - "Rome, Anzio, Charley in Rome" (Box 31, Folder 171)
      - "Rome area?" (Box 31, Folder 172)
      - "Rome, Florence" [includes images of art dump at Campo Tures, Cranach's Adam and Eve] (Box 31, Folder 173)
      - "Rome, other, American cemetery" (Box 32, Folder 174)
      - "Rome, Padua, Florence" (Box 32, Folder 175)
      - "Salio" (Box 32, Folder 176)
      - "Salio, jeep" (Box 32, Folder 177)
      - "Salio, Jugoslavia, SS Rex" (Box 32, Folder 178)
      - "Salio, L. Garda" (Box 32, Folder 179)
      - "San G[illeg]" [San Gimignano?] (Box 32, Folder 180)
      - "San Leonardo, Castle Dareuskus and SS trophies" (Box 32, Folder 181)
      - "San Minuto, Monttlupo" (Box 32, Folder 182)
      - "Slides taken of these" (Box 32, Folder 183)
      - Teatro Farnese (Box 32, Folder 184)
      - "Torro del Lago, north of Arno" (Box 32, Folder 185)
      - "Train to Florence" [art return] (Box 32, Folder 186)
      - "Velletri, breakout Anzio" (Box 33, Folder 187)
      - "Venice" (Box 33, Folder 188)
      - "Venice, Padua, Arena Chapel" (Box 33, Folder 189)
      - "Verona area? Italian war posters" (Box 33, Folder 190)
      - "Wilcox, Red Cross" (Box 33, Folder 191)
      - "Yugoslavia" (Box 33, Folder 192)
      - Unidentified (Box 33, Folder 193 - 200)
    - Envelopes [negatives]
      - "Pisa, Florence mostly", undated (Box 33, Folder 201)
      - "Salerno landing", undated (Box 33, Folder 202)
    - Loose [positives]
      - "Classified" [Unites States government classification], 1944-1945 (Box 34, Folder 203)
      - German [mostly German military photographs], undated (Box 34, Folder 204)
    - People
      - Keller, Deane, 1943-1945, undated (Box 34, Folder 205)
      - Mussolini death scenes, undated (Box 34, Folder 206)
      - Others
        - Identified [alpha by name], 1944-1945, undated (Box 34, Folder 207)
        - Unidentified, undated (Box 34, Folder 208)
      - Places
        - A-Z, undated (Box 34, Folder 209)
        - Anzio, undated (Box 34, Folder 210)
        - Florence, undated (Box 34, Folder 211)
        - Lucca Cathedral [liberation celebration], 1944 (Box 34, Folder 212)
        - Naples, undated (Box 35, Folder 213)
        - Paesteum, undated (Box 35, Folder 214)
        - Pisa, undated (Box 35, Folder 215)
        - San Fedrano jail, undated (Box 35, Folder 216)
        - Unidentified, undated (Box 35, Folder 217)
      - War damage and art salvation efforts
        - General [alpha by location], 1942-1944, undated (Box 35, Folder 218 - 219)
        - Select
          - Allied Military Government art return ceremony, Florence, undated (Box 36, Folder 220)
          - Campo Tures, Alto Adige, undated (Box 36, Folder 221)
          - Cosimo di Medici [return of equestrian statue to Florence], undated (Box 36, Folder 222)
          - Florence [includes images of Uffizi Gallery, Masaccio's Brancacci Chapel], 1945, undated (Box 36, Folder 223)
          - Naples, undated (Box 36, Folder 224)
          - Pisa, Campo Santo, undated (Box 36, Folder 225)
          - Postcards [of damaged monuments in original states], undated (Box 36, Folder 226)
          - San Leonardo, 1945, undated (Box 36, Folder 227)
          - Unidentified, 1945, undated (Box 36, Folder 228)
    - Loose [negatives, unidentified], undated (Box 36, Folder 229)
  - Wartime publications
    - English, 1943-1946, undated (Box 37, Folder 230 - 235)
    - German, 1940, 1944, undated (Box 38, Folder 236 - 237)
    - Italian, 1936-1948, undated (Box 39, Folder 238 - 242)
- Professional, 1914-1980; Series IV
  Professional is comprised of four sections: Artworks, Books, Client files, and Clippings. This series provides excellent documentation of Keller's artistic development, his thriving portrait practice, and his relationships with his clients.
  Artworks is arranged by subject and contains both photographs and actual artworks. The photographs comprise an extensive survey of Keller's artwork outside his portrait practice, including allegorical works from his student years, anatomical drawings, landscape studies, and early mural commissions. The section also contains a limited but vibrant selection of actual artworks. Sketches include fully worked drawings dating from Keller's time at the American Academy in Rome, designs for murals, and charcoal studies of portrait clients. Watercolors contain several small, well-preserved studies for larger portraits.
  Books is arranged by title and include a rare example of Keller's work as an illustrator, On Sepulchres, a project he undertook with fellow Yale employees. In addition there are materials gathered for an unpublished volume on Keller's numerous portraits of individuals associated with Yale. They are a useful, although incomplete, survey of Keller portraits in the university collection.
  Client files is the largest section in the series and is arranged by client name. The files are a superb resource for study of Keller's career as a modern portrait painter, offering information on his clientele, practice, and painting methods. The number of the files indicates the breadth and volume of Keller's portrait practice and the continuing demand for painted portraits in the age of mechanical reproduction. The exact content of each file varies, but most include correspondence concerning sittings, the painting, desired revisions, or issues of payment; photographs of the sitter used as an aide (or direct source) for the finished product; and images of the final portrait. A client file allows the reader to trace the development of a portrait, compare the subject with the painted depiction, and gain insight into the painter-patron relationship. Keller's own perspectives on his work as a portraitist can also be found in Series V. Writings under "Portrait and Figure Painting" and "The Professional as Art Critic."
  The Clippings section, arranged in the order in which it was received, is comprised of numerous newspaper, magazine and exhibit catalogues. They document Keller's career as a painter, teacher, and portraitist.
  - Artworks
    - Allegorical paintings [photographs], undated (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - Landscapes [photographs], undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Murals [photograph], undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Self-Portrait [photographs, includes images of Keller at work in his studio], undated (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - Sketchbooks, 1914-1915, undated (Box 40, Folder 5 - 6)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
      Separated Materials
      See also: box 53, folder 4
    - Watercolors, undated
      See: box 53, folder 5
    - Works-in-progress [photographs], undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous [photographs], undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Books
    - On Sepulchres
      - Author's copy, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 10)
      - Correspondence, 1970-1973, undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
      - Illustration proofs, undated (Box 41, Folder 12)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
      - Photographs [of paintings done by Keller for the book], 1971, undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - "The Yale Portraits of Deane Keller"
      - Correspondence, 1974-1980, undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
      - Photographs [collected for proposed edition], undated (Box 41, Folder 17 - 20)
  - Client Files
    - Lists, 1953-1974, undated (Box 42, Folder 21 - 22)
    - Notebooks, 1947-1963 (Box 42, Folder 23 - 24)
    - Portraits [photographs of unidentified completed portraits] (Box 43, Folder 25 - 31)
    - Individuals
      - Adams, J. C. (Box 43, Folder 32)
      - Alcorn, Howard (Box 43, Folder 33)
      - Allen (Box 43, Folder 34)
      - Altschul, Frank (Box 43, Folder 35)
      - Anderson (Box 43, Folder 36)
      - Angell, James R. (Box 43, Folder 37)
      - Aulisi, Felix (Box 43, Folder 38)
      - Anthony, Louise (Box 43, Folder 39)
      - Armstrong, John (Box 43, Folder 40)
      - Arnstain (Box 43, Folder 41)
      - Ashley, Thomas (Box 43, Folder 42)
      - Askanase, Reuben (Box 43, Folder 43)
      - Atwater, Frank (Box 43, Folder 44)
      - Babbidge, Homer (Box 43, Folder 45)
      - Bainton, Roland (Box 43, Folder 46)
      - Baker, George P. (Box 43, Folder 47)
      - Bakke, E. Wight (Box 43, Folder 48)
      - Barker, Dr. Creighton (Box 43, Folder 49)
      - Baldwin, Justice Raymond (Box 43, Folder 50)
      - Barnes, Kenneth (Box 43, Folder 51)
      - Barnett, Herman (Box 43, Folder 52)
      - Barron, Donald (Box 43, Folder 53)
      - Bartholomew, Marshall (Box 43, Folder 54)
      - Baumgartner, Elsie (Box 43, Folder 55)
      - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope (Box 43, Folder 56)
      - Beach, Pat (Box 43, Folder 57)
      - Beckerman, Martha (Box 43, Folder 58)
      - Beers, Henry S. (Box 43, Folder 59)
      - Bellinger, Alfred (Box 43, Folder 60)
      - Bernholz, Charles (Box 43, Folder 61)
      - Bishop, Peter (Box 43, Folder 62)
      - Blair, Edwin F. (Box 43, Folder 63)
      - Bloss, Meredith (Box 43, Folder 64)
      - Borgerson (Box 43, Folder 65)
      - Bower (Box 43, Folder 66)
      - Brackett, Mabel (Box 43, Folder 67)
      - Brennan, Katherine (Box 43, Folder 68)
      - Brewster, Kingman (Box 43, Folder 69)
      - Brownell, Samuel (Box 43, Folder 70)
      - Buckland (Box 43, Folder 71)
      - Bunnell, Frank (Box 43, Folder 72)
      - Burke, Harry (Box 43, Folder 73)
      - Burke, Lillian (Box 43, Folder 74)
      - Calhoun, R. (Box 43, Folder 75)
      - Callahan, Frank (Box 43, Folder 76)
      - Carmody, Martin (Box 43, Folder 77)
      - Carson, Mrs. Gerald (Box 43, Folder 78)
      - Caulfield, Norton (Box 43, Folder 79)
      - Celentano, William C. (Box 43, Folder 80)
      - Clarke, Claire (Box 43, Folder 81)
      - Clarke, Clement C. (Box 43, Folder 82)
      - Coffin (Box 43, Folder 83)
      - Cole, Jack (Box 43, Folder 84)
      - Conway, Herbert (Box 43, Folder 85 - 86)
      - Cooper, James W. (Box 43, Folder 87)
      - Crapo, Betty (Box 43, Folder 88)
      - Crawford, George W. (Box 43, Folder 89)
      - Creech, Oscar (Box 43, Folder 90)
      - Cruikshank, Paul (Box 43, Folder 91)
      - Cudworth, James R. (Box 44, Folder 92)
      - Cushing, Harvey (Box 44, Folder 93)
      - Cutler, Robert (Box 44, Folder 94)
      - Daggett, David (Box 44, Folder 95)
      - Davey (Box 44, Folder 96)
      - Davidson, George (Box 44, Folder 97)
      - Davie, M. R. (Box 44, Folder 98)
      - Davis, John M. K. (Box 44, Folder 99)
      - Day (Box 44, Folder 100)
      - Deming, Clyde (Box 44, Folder 101)
      - Desmond, Charles (Box 44, Folder 102)
      - DeVane, William (Box 44, Folder 103)
      - Dickey, Jean (Box 44, Folder 104)
      - Dixon, Homer W. (Box 44, Folder 105)
      - Dodds (Box 44, Folder 106)
      - Dodge, Marshall (Box 44, Folder 107)
      - Drew, Rev. Bernard (Box 44, Folder 108)
      - Eisenhardt, Louise (Box 44, Folder 109)
      - Eliot, Jared (Box 44, Folder 110)
      - Ely [with inscription by Keller, giving title as "Ely Sisters"] (Box 44, Folder 111)
      - Esty, John (Box 44, Folder 112)
      - Farr, H. A. (Box 44, Folder 113)
      - Farrell, Franklin (Box 44, Folder 114)
      - Fersen, Countess Lili (Box 44, Folder 115)
      - Fisher, Benjamin (Box 44, Folder 116)
      - Fry, C. C. (Box 44, Folder 117)
      - Fusco, Luigi (Box 44, Folder 118)
      - Gaillard, Ned (Box 44, Folder 119)
      - German, Dr. William [group portrait] (Box 44, Folder 120)
      - Gertz, Louis (Box 44, Folder 121)
      - Gertz, Samuel (Box 44, Folder 122)
      - Gettemy, James N. (Box 44, Folder 123)
      - Gibbons, Lee (Box 44, Folder 124)
      - Gibson, William (Box 44, Folder 125)
      - Gilmore, Mrs. (Box 44, Folder 126)
      - Gilson, John L. (Box 44, Folder 127)
      - Glenn, Frank (Box 44, Folder 128)
      - Goulian, Dr. Dicran (Box 44, Folder 129)
      - Grant, Frederick (Box 44, Folder 130)
      - Gray, Bowman (Box 44, Folder 131)
      - Gregory, Herbert E. (Box 44, Folder 132)
      - Griswold (Box 44, Folder 133)
      - Griswold, A. Whitney (Box 44, Folder 134)
      - Guida, Bartholomew (Box 44, Folder 135)
      - Gunderson, Sven (Box 44, Folder 136)
      - Gute (Box 44, Folder 137)
      - Haggard, Howard (Box 44, Folder 138)
      - Hall, William E. (Box 44, Folder 139)
      - Hamilton, T. Stewart (Box 44, Folder 140)
      - Hansen, Eric (Box 44, Folder 141)
      - Harris, James (Box 44, Folder 142)
      - Harvey, Samuel (Box 44, Folder 143)
      - Harwell (Box 44, Folder 144)
      - Havemeyer, Julia Loomis (Box 44, Folder 145)
      - Havemeyer, Loomis (Box 44, Folder 146)
      - Hendrick, Mrs. James P. (Box 44, Folder 147)
      - Hendrickson, George (Box 44, Folder 148)
      - Hern, Edward (Box 44, Folder 149)
      - Hines (Box 44, Folder 150)
      - Hiscock, Dr. Ira (Box 44, Folder 151)
      - Hodge, Robert (Box 44, Folder 152)
      - Holden, Benjamin (Box 44, Folder 153)
      - Hoover, Herbert (Box 44, Folder 154)
      - Horsfall, James (Box 44, Folder 155)
      - House, Charles (Box 44, Folder 156)
      - Howard, Gilmore (Box 44, Folder 157)
      - Islieb, Horace (Box 44, Folder 158)
      - Jackson, R. S. (Box 44, Folder 159)
      - Jehlinger, Charles (Box 44, Folder 160)
      - Jenkins, John F. (Box 44, Folder 161)
      - Jones, Donald (Box 44, Folder 162)
      - Kalamazoo, Stanley (Box 44, Folder 163)
      - Keith, Barker (Box 44, Folder 164)
      - Keith, Rev. (Box 44, Folder 165)
      - Kelley, Alden (Box 44, Folder 166)
      - Kelly, Colin D. (Box 44, Folder 167)
      - Kelly, Margaret (Box 44, Folder 168)
      - Kendall, William S. (Box 44, Folder 169)
      - Kiphuth, Bob [group portrait of Yale swimming coach and team] (Box 45, Folder 170)
      - Kirchner, John (Box 45, Folder 171)
      - Kirkwood, Robert C. (Box 45, Folder 172)
      - Kiselewski, Joseph (Box 45, Folder 173)
      - Knights of Columbus (Box 45, Folder 174)
      - Labaree, Leonard (Box 45, Folder 175)
      - Landers, Mrs. (Box 45, Folder 176)
      - Larson, Roger (Box 45, Folder 177)
      - Lee, Richard (Box 45, Folder 178)
      - Leggett, John D. (Box 45, Folder 179)
      - Leman, Monte (Box 45, Folder 180)
      - Liebert, Herman W. (Box 45, Folder 181)
      - Livingston, Elizabeth (Box 45, Folder 182)
      - Lockwood, Theodore (Box 45, Folder 183)
      - Lodge, Gov. John (Box 45, Folder 184)
      - Logan, James P. (Box 45, Folder 185)
      - Long, Dr. (Box 45, Folder 186)
      - Lovett, Rev. Sidney (Box 45, Folder 187)
      - Lunt, Storer (Box 45, Folder 188)
      - Luquiens, F. B. (Box 45, Folder 189)
      - Lyman, John (Box 45, Folder 190)
      - MacAllister, Ian (Box 45, Folder 191)
      - Marcy, Howard (Box 45, Folder 192)
      - Marion, Mrs. John (Box 45, Folder 193)
      - Matthews, Miss (Box 45, Folder 194)
      - Matthewson, Champion H. (Box 45, Folder 195)
      - McCain, James A. (Box 45, Folder 196)
      - McConnel, Rachel (Box 45, Folder 197)
      - McDevitt, John W. (Box 45, Folder 198)
      - McDonnell, Ralph (Box 45, Folder 199)
      - McLaughlin, Commodore John Thomas (Box 45, Folder 200)
      - McMannus, Frank (Box 45, Folder 201)
      - McOrmond, Raymond (Box 45, Folder 202)
      - Meeks, Everett (Box 45, Folder 203)
      - Meigs, John (Box 45, Folder 204)
      - Meigs, Mrs. (Box 45, Folder 205)
      - Melhorn, Nathan R. (Box 45, Folder 206)
      - Mendell, C. W. (Box 45, Folder 207)
      - Merriman, Daniel (Box 45, Folder 208)
      - Middleton, Keith T. (Box 45, Folder 209)
      - Milikowsky Mrs. Matthew (Box 45, Folder 210)
      - Miller, David (Box 45, Folder 211)
      - Miller, Helen (Box 45, Folder 212)
      - Models (Box 45, Folder 213)
      - Moe, Henry Allen (Box 45, Folder 214)
      - Montana, Isabel de (Box 45, Folder 215)
      - Moore, John (Box 45, Folder 216)
      - Moorley, Theodore (Box 45, Folder 217)
      - Morningstar, Joseph V. (Box 45, Folder 218)
      - Muirhead, David (Box 45, Folder 219)
      - Mullen (Box 45, Folder 220)
      - Nelson, Clarence (Box 45, Folder 221)
      - Nicholas, T. S. (Box 45, Folder 222)
      - Nickerson, Kingsbury S. (Box 45, Folder 223)
      - Noah, Bernice (Box 45, Folder 224)
      - Noe (Box 45, Folder 225)
      - Northrop, Phillip (Box 45, Folder 226)
      - O'Brien, John L. (Box 45, Folder 227)
      - Ohse (Box 45, Folder 228)
      - Osterweis, Rollin (Box 45, Folder 229)
      - O'Sullivan, Patrick B. (Box 45, Folder 230)
      - Paier, Adele K. (Box 45, Folder 231)
      - Perlroth, William (Box 45, Folder 232)
      - Perry, Pres. (Box 45, Folder 233)
      - Peterson, Marvin (Box 45, Folder 234)
      - Petronovich (Box 45, Folder 235)
      - Petryn, Andrew (Box 45, Folder 236)
      - Phillipe (Box 45, Folder 237)
      - Pierson, George (Box 45, Folder 238)
      - Pollak, S. (Box 45, Folder 239)
      - Powers, Grover (Box 45, Folder 240)
      - Powers, John H. (Box 46, Folder 241)
      - Pulling, Edward (Box 46, Folder 242)
      - Quaile, George (Box 46, Folder 243)
      - Quinnipiak Club (Box 46, Folder 244)
      - Rathbone, M. J. (Box 46, Folder 245)
      - Rauch, Richard (Box 46, Folder 246)
      - Reade, Edwin G. (Box 46, Folder 247)
      - Riely, Beth (Box 46, Folder 248)
      - Robinson, Barclay (Box 46, Folder 249)
      - Rockwell, Clara (Box 46, Folder 250)
      - Rodewald, Elizabeth (Box 46, Folder 251)
      - Rogers, James (Box 46, Folder 252)
      - Ruckgaber (Box 46, Folder 253)
      - Rulon-Miller, Richmond (Box 46, Folder 254)
      - Ryle, Anne (Box 46, Folder 255)
      - Sachs, Ernest (Box 46, Folder 256)
      - Sanford, William (Box 46, Folder 257)
      - Schiavone, Joseph (Box 46, Folder 258)
      - Schnelle, Gerald (Box 46, Folder 259)
      - Schnitzer (Box 46, Folder 260)
      - Schoen, Herbert P. (Box 46, Folder 261)
      - Schuchert, Charles (Box 46, Folder 262)
      - Sewell (Box 46, Folder 263)
      - Sharp, Thelma (Box 46, Folder 264)
      - Sheritt, Arthur (Box 46, Folder 265)
      - Sherk, Allen (Box 46, Folder 266)
      - Shorts, Perry (Box 46, Folder 267)
      - Sibley, John (Box 46, Folder 268)
      - Sizer, T. (Box 46, Folder 269)
      - Slate, William (Box 46, Folder 270)
      - Smith, Dr. George H. (Box 46, Folder 271)
      - Smith, Dr. Howard (Box 46, Folder 272)
      - Smith, Miss Wilnor (Box 46, Folder 273)
      - Snowden, George H. (Box 46, Folder 274)
      - Snyder, B. E. (Box 46, Folder 275)
      - Southport Church (Box 46, Folder 276)
      - Sperry, Sereno (Box 46, Folder 277)
      - Spoerl, Clifford A. (Box 46, Folder 278)
      - Sprenger, Rev. William (Box 46, Folder 279)
      - Stanley, Arthur (Box 46, Folder 280)
      - Steinert, Alan (Box 46, Folder 281)
      - Sterling, James (Box 46, Folder 282)
      - Sterne, Augustus (Box 46, Folder 283)
      - Sterne, Edgar (Box 46, Folder 284)
      - Stiles, Ezra (Box 46, Folder 285)
      - Stoeckel, R. B. (Box 46, Folder 286)
      - Strickland, William (Box 46, Folder 287)
      - Sturges, George (Box 46, Folder 288)
      - Sullivan, "Red" (Box 46, Folder 289)
      - Sullivan, William (Box 46, Folder 290)
      - Taft, Harry (Box 46, Folder 291)
      - Taft, Howard (Box 46, Folder 292)
      - Taft, Peter (Box 46, Folder 293)
      - Taft, Robert (Box 46, Folder 294)
      - Taft, William Howard (Box 46, Folder 295)
      - Taft School (Box 46, Folder 296)
      - Tator, Samuel (Box 46, Folder 297)
      - Tator, Mrs. Samuel (Box 46, Folder 298)
      - Taylor (Box 46, Folder 299)
      - Thayer, Sylvanus (Box 46, Folder 300)
      - Thomas, Arnon (Box 46, Folder 301)
      - Thorne, Peter (Box 46, Folder 302)
      - Tinker, C. B. (Box 46, Folder 303)
      - Title, Melvin (Box 46, Folder 304)
      - Trudeau, Francis B. (Box 46, Folder 305)
      - Trust Company of Georgia (Box 46, Folder 306)
      - Vachon, Edmond (Box 46, Folder 307)
      - Vaill, George D. (Box 46, Folder 308)
      - Van Wyck, Phillip (Box 46, Folder 309)
      - Verdi, William F. (Box 47, Folder 310)
      - Wald, Florence (Box 47, Folder 311)
      - Watson, Marvin (Box 47, Folder 312)
      - Watson, William (Box 47, Folder 313)
      - Whiteman, John B. (Box 47, Folder 314)
      - Whitney (Box 47, Folder 315)
      - Wiggin (Box 47, Folder 316)
      - Wiggin, Mrs. Frederick (Box 47, Folder 317)
      - Wilson, Andy (Box 47, Folder 318)
      - Wilson, Hugh (Box 47, Folder 319)
      - Wineland, Mrs. (Box 47, Folder 320)
      - Yale University (Box 47, Folder 321)
      - Unidentified (Box 47, Folder 322 - 332)
    - Scrapbook [photographs of individual portraits, some identified, some unidentified, removed from small scrapbook] (Box 47, Folder 333)
  - Clippings (Box 48, Folder 334 - 347)
  - Clippings (Box 49, Folder 334 - 347)
  - Clippings (Box 50, Folder 334 - 347)
- Writings, 1936-1978; Series V
  Writings is comprised of various short pieces by Keller, arranged alphabetically by title or theme. Titles given by Keller appear in quotation marks. All other works are identified by theme. Writings include graduation speeches, letters to the editor, and art historical discourses. This series is especially rich in insight into Keller's practice and philosophy as an artist. "Head and Figure Painting," "Portrait and Figure Painting," and Oil Painting document Keller's painting technique and use of materials. Art Schools, Letters to the Editor, "The Professional as Art Critic," and Traditional v. Abstract outline his thoughts on the teaching of art, including commentary on the Yale School of Art and his defense of naturalistic painting in a modernist era.
  - "An Account of Thanksgiving", 1960 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Alexandria Hospital graduation speech, 1962 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Art schools, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "A Confession of Faith", undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Development of draftsmanship, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Drama students [lecture to], undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Head and Figure Painting", 1963 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "History of American Painting", undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Howard Pyle", undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Letters to the editor, 1959, 1975, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Lodge, Governor John [concerning Keller's portrait of the governor of Connecticut], undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Memorials, 1978, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Oil painting, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Paier Art School [commencement speeches], 1973, 1975, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "The Pictorial Life of Benjamin Franklin", undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - "Portrait and Figure Painting", undated (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - Portrait painting [first lecture on], 1952 (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - "The Portraits of Washington", undated (Box 51, Folder 1)